<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entries on Joe Bacchus George</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/entries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entries on Joe Bacchus George</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/entries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A prime counting function with trigonometry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entries/prime_counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entries/prime_counting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;prime counting function (PCF)&lt;/strong&gt; counts the number of prime numbers less than or equal to a given number $x$. We denote it by $\Pi(x)$ and asymptotically obeys&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$&#xA;\Pi(x) \sim \frac{x}{\log(x)}, \quad x \to \infty.&#xA;$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;strong&gt;prime number theorem&lt;/strong&gt;, and it reveals the case that the density of primes decreases as we get to larger numbers. Computing this quantity exactly for arbitary $x$ is not straightforward. I here propose a ridiculous and intractable solution, which is exact in the limit&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Erroneous Measurement-Based Quantum Computing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entries/mbqc_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entries/mbqc_thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paradigm of &lt;strong&gt;measurement-based quantum computing (MBQC)&lt;/strong&gt; uses careful sequences of measurements on entangled qunatum states to perform computation. Because the approach can be erroneous, and naturally expressible in the diagrammatic language of the ZX-Calculus, there exists a nice interplay between the graphical representation and physical faulty lattices that contain the system. &lt;strong&gt;Percolation theory&lt;/strong&gt;, which studies the behaviour of graphs when you remove some of their components, helps describe the limitations in computational power when the quantum resources are imperfect. These ideas are brought together &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.ox.ac.uk/people/aleks.kissinger/theses/george-thesis.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hidden innovation from patent networks at the Bartlett</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entries/casa_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entries/casa_networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patents tend to cite other innovations that inspired them, from which directed graphs can be constructed. One can then identify the categories that these innovations fall under by exploiting their International Patent Classification (IPC) codes at various hierarchical levels. The resulting graphs can be used to identify the most productive ideas in a given field, strongly influential categories of patents and some predictive ability over future innovations. &lt;a href=&#34;../../annotated_presentation.pdf&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; are some snapshots of some briefly annotated slides that explore the project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internal Chatbot for the ATLAS Experiment at CERN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entries/cern_chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entries/cern_chatbot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;ATLAS collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; at CERN is one of the largest particle physics experiments in the world, and accordingly produces a vast amount of data and resources that can be difficult to navigate. In order to overcome this, a proposal was made to integrate &lt;strong&gt;retrieval-augmented generation (RAG)&lt;/strong&gt; techniques into a chatbot interface which would enable researchers and doctoral students in finding relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the ambition was to be able to link results back to the original sources from which it provided information, so as to allow researches to conduct subsequent investigations. Slides are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://indico.cern.ch/event/1395528/contributions/5877957/attachments/2833825/4951736/chATLAS%20IML%20Meeting%20(1).pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://indico.bnl.gov/event/19560/contributions/83300/attachments/51306/87732/Chatlas%20Overview.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
